
//Question Bank
/*
  {
    category: 'General GCIH CCNA',     
    difficulty: 'Easy Medium Hard'      
    question: '',
    answer: '',
    hint: '',
    blank: '',
    review: '<>',
  },
*/

let questions = [
    {
      category: 'GCIH',
      question: 'What application uses hook.js to attack victims from the browser?',
      answer: 'BeEF',
      hint: 'MOOOOO',
      blank: 'xxxx',
      review: '<https://youtu.be/etqw6MpisYw?si=c2ae_m0xywwBGZan>'
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is the OSI model?',
      answer: 'Open Systems Interconnection',
      hint: 'https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/osi-model/',
      blank: 'xxxx xxxxxxx xxxxxxxxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://youtu.be/Ilk7UXzV_Qc?si=eFvm1JMCByP6iwJ1>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What do vlans do?',
      answer: 'logically segment',
      hint: 'physical vs logical does what?',
      blank: 'xxxxxxxxx xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.techtarget.com/searchnetworking/definition/virtual-LAN>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is Phishing?',
      answer: ['Email scam', 'email'],
      hint: 'What is it sent over?',
      blank: 'xxxxx xxxx',
      review: '<https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/email-security/what-is-phishing.html>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is a DOS attack',
      answer: 'Denial of service',
      hint: 'What does it stop?',
      blank: 'xxxxxx xx xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/ddos/glossary/denial-of-service/>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is a botnet?',
      answer: 'Many compromised devices',
      hint: 'Controlled by attackers',
      blank: 'xxxx xxxxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/cyberpedia/what-is-botnet>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'how many USABLE hosts can fit on a /26 subnet?',
      answer: '62',
      hint: 'amount subtract 1 for network address and one for broadcast address',
      blank: 'xx',
      review: '<https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/cidr/>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is the difference between layer 2 switch and a layer 3 switch?',
      answer: 'routing',
      hint: 'Layer 3 act similiar to a router.',
      blank: 'xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://planetechusa.com/layer-2-vs-layer-3-switches/>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What port is RDP?',
      answer: '3389',
      hint: 'remote desktop protocol.',
      blank: 'xxxx',
      review: '<https://www.cbtnuggets.com/common-ports/what-is-port-3389>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What port is LDAP?',
      answer: '389',
      hint: 'Lightweight Directory Access Protocol.',
      blank: 'xxx',
      review: '<https://www.cbtnuggets.com/blog/technology/networking/ldap-port-389-vs-636>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What port is LDAPS?',
      answer: '636',
      hint: 'Encrypted Lightweight Directory Access Protocol.',
      blank: 'xxx',
      review: '<https://www.cbtnuggets.com/blog/technology/networking/ldap-port-389-vs-636>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is the C in the CIA triad?',
      answer: 'confidentiality',
      hint: 'c is for data to be kept secret or private',
      blank: 'xxxxxxxxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.fortinet.com/resources/cyberglossary/cia-triad>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'Who owns the IPs 1.1.1.1, 1.0.0.1, 1.1.1.2, 1.0.0.2, 1.1.1.3, 1.0.0.3?',
      answer: 'cloudflare',
      hint: 'The best dns resolver!',
      blank: 'xxxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/dns/what-is-1.1.1.1/>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is the I in the CIA triad?',
      answer: 'Integrity',
      hint: 'I is trustworthy and free from tampering',
      blank: 'xxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/definition/Confidentiality-integrity-and-availability-CIA>',
    },
    {
      category: 'General',
      question: 'What is the A in the CIA triad?',
      answer: 'availability',
      hint: 'a is systems, networks, and applications must be functioning as they should and when they should',
      blank: 'xxxxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://informationsecurity.wustl.edu/items/confidentiality-integrity-and-availability-the-cia-triad/>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CCNA',
      question: 'What model of operation does Hot Standby Router Protocol (HSRP) use?',
      answer: 'Active/passive',
      hint: 'one router is on standby while the other is working',
      blank: 'xxxxxx/xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/ip/hot-standby-router-protocol-hsrp/9234-hsrpguidetoc.html>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CCNA',
      question: 'What layer # is port security and dynamic ARP inspection?',
      answer: '2',
      hint: 'NOT 3',
      blank: 'x',
      review: '<https://info.pivitglobal.com/resources/port-security-layer-2-protection>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CCNA',
      question: 'Which type of message is sent by DHCP client to ask to lease a specific IP address from a DHCP server?',
      answer: 'Request',
      hint: 'DORA',
      blank: 'xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://notes.networklessons.com/dhcp-message-types>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'Which analysis framework provides the most explicit detail regarding how to mitigate or detect a given threat?',
      answer: 'MITRE ATT&CK framework',
      hint: 'Lockheed, diamond or MITRE',
      blank: 'xxxxx xxx&xx xxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://attack.mitre.org/>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'What encryption method is excellent at verifying disk & file integrity?',
      answer: 'SHA-256',
      hint: 'SHA-xxx',
      blank: 'xxx-xxx',
      review: '<https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/9004655?hl=en>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'Which of the following types of data breaches would require that the US Department of Health and Human Services and the media be notified if more than 500 individuals are affected by a data breach?',
      answer: 'Protected health information',
      hint: 'PHI',
      blank: 'xxxxxxxxx xxxxxx xxxxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.niu.edu/doit/about/policies/hipaa-breach-notification-rule.shtml>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'Which type of threat actor can accidentally or inadvertently cause a security incident in your organization?',
      answer: 'Insider threat',
      hint: 'It could be you!',
      blank: 'xxxxxxx xxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.opentext.com/what-is/insider-threat>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'What should be done NEXT if the final set of security controls does not eliminate all of the risks in a given system?',
      answer: 'accept',
      hint: 'can you do anything more?',
      blank: 'xxxxxx',
      review: '<>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'What technology would allow your company to provide a secure SSO solution for accessing both the corporate wireless network and its network resources?',
      answer: 'RADIUS',
      hint: 'not WPA2, WPS, or WEP',
      blank: 'xxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.fortinet.com/resources/cyberglossary/radius-protocol>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'An attacker has been collecting credit card details by calling victims and using false pretexts to trick them?',
      answer: 'Vishing',
      hint: 'Voice what?',
      blank: 'xxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://www.terranovasecurity.com/solutions/security-awareness-training/what-is-vishing>',
    },
    {
      category: 'CompTIA Security+',
      question: 'What is the agreement that specify what is allowed during a penetration test?',
      answer: 'Rules of engagement',
      hint: 'ROE',
      blank: 'xxxxx xx xxxxxxxxxxx',
      review: '<https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/rules_of_engagement>',
    }
];

module.exports = questions;